Guide to the Cook family papers, 1795-1898
Cook family papers, 1795-1898
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cook family papers, 1795-1898.
4409
Cook family.
.4 cubic ft.
Indentures, bonds, mortgage notes, farm survey maps, stock and financial reports, wills, newspapers, photographs, military records, political items, genealogical items, obituaries, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Indentures, bonds, mortgage notes, farm survey maps, stock and financial reports, wills, newspapers, and family photographs of various members of the Cook family of Kirkland, Oneida County, N.Y. Other documents are Chauncy Cook's army appointment and discharge papers and other personal papers including his mss. will; Constable Curtiss' expense list for serving warrants and subpoenas; political items; Cook family genealogical items; and obituaries for Cook and Hart family members.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Indentures, bonds, mortgage notes, farm survey maps, stock and financial reports, wills, newspapers, and family photographs of various members of the Cook family of Kirkland, Oneida County, N.Y. Other documents are Chauncy Cook's army appointment and discharge papers (1824-1828) and other personal papers including his mss. will (July 27, 1868); Constable Curtiss' expense list for serving warrants and subpoenas (1856); political items; Cook family genealogical items; and obituaries for Cook and Hart family members.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cook family.; Cook, Chauncy.; Hart family.
Subjects:
Family--New York (State)--Oneida County; Family--New York (State)--Kirkland.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographic prints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Land Indentures, Sept. 15 & 22, 1795 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Land Indenture (in fragments), Feb. 25, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Manuscript Land Indenture between Thomas Hart, B.U. Smith, Henry McNeil and Josiah Cook., Dec. 31, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Land Indentures. (Fragmented.), Aug. 17, 1819, Oct. 22, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Appropriations to Colleges in New York State., ca. 1812-1850 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Manuscript Will of Elisha Hills., Apr. 25, 1822 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- List of Contributors for the erection of a Parsonage in the Town of Augusta, N.Y. (Oneida County) for $1,000., Mar. 2, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Map drawn and surveyed by Amos Osborn. (Fragmented.), Nov. 21, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mortgage Notes. Also, one Manuscript Land Division Document to various people mentioned., Nov. 22, 1826 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Land Indenture between Rebecca and Winthrop Chandler and Chauncy C. Cook., Feb. 23, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Two Bonds: Between Ira H. Hills and Chauncy C. Cook, and between Seth Hills and David L. Barton, Julius Candar and William Osborn., Nov. 13, June 5, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Legacy of Elisha Hills and Polly Warrinner to Elisha S. Hills., May 19, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Two Bonds, between Ira Hills and James Lumbard, and Sarah Gates and Chauncy C. Cook., Apr. 14, 1843; Oct. 24, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Land Indentures., Oct. 22, 1841; Mar. 26, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Farm Survey Map drawn by Gaius Butler., Aug. 21, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Two Deeds: between Chauncy C. Cook and various people undersigned on the document., Aug. 1, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Town of Kirkland Supervisor's Report., 1845 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Manuscript Stock and Financial Statements., 1848, 1853-1854 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Constable Horatio Curtiss' expense list for serving warrants and subpoenas., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Records and other papers of Chauncy C. Cook., 1824-1865 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chauncy C. Cook's Will. (He died Apr. 1867.) Death Certificate and cemetery deed are also enclosed., July 27, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Esther E. Cook's Will. (Mother of Elisha H. Cook, Frances [Fanny] Cook and Marion E. Hart.) Other Hart family items are enclosed., May 26, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Cook Family Genealogy. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Newspapers., 1842-1860, 1888, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Obituaries. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Political Items., 1851-1854 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- One 2" letter box of Cook, Miller and Hart family photographs, including some original pressed flowers, Grandmother Cook's needlecase, an original pen and ink sketch of a Dickens character dated Jan. 23, 1914, and "Attic School" children. (Box 2)